waterfordwhispersnews.com 2019-06-30

# Privacy – Waterford Whispers News

## Privacy Policy

This website, waterfordwhispersnews.com and associated apps is owned and operated by Whispers Media Ltd.

In this Privacy Policy, when we refer to “waterfordwhispersnews.com”, we mean the digital network operated by waterfordwhispersnews.com, or its parent companies, subsidiaries and affiliates.

waterfordwhispersnews.com is fully compliant with The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) (EU) 2016/679, which is in effect from May 25th 2018.

## Right to Privacy

waterfordwhispersnews.com respects your right to privacy. Any information we collect, be it non-personalised or personalised, will be treated with the highest standards of security and confidentiality, strictly in accordance with The General Data Protection Regulation. waterfordwhispersnews.com strictly only works with fully data compliant partners.

Collection and use of personal information  
waterfordwhispersnews.com collects non-personalised and personalised data in three main ways:  
Information that you actively volunteer, such as email newsletter registration and similar.  
Analytics: This allows waterfordwhispersnews.com to measure the number of visits to the website and helps inform us as to how to improve the website for visitors.  
Advertising: Advertisers on waterfordwhispersnews.com use cookies to inform, optimise and serve ads based on your browsing activities and interests.  
We never share this information with any third parties without your explicit consent.

For more information on how to manage your cookies please visit our [Cookie Policy](https://waterfordwhispersnews.com/your-privacy-settings/).

## The information we collect:

### Advertising

Advertisements on waterfordwhispersnews.com can be of a non-personalised or personalised nature. The information collected by advertisers helps them to gauge the effectiveness of their campaigns and may limit the number of times you see an advertisement. For more information and details of how to manage how advertising works on waterfordwhispersnews.com, read our [Cookies Policy](https://waterfordwhispersnews.com/your-privacy-settings/).

### Using Facebook to comment

When commenting on waterfordwhispersnews.com you use your Facebook account to comment on an article, we  **DO NOT** collect any facebook data associated with your facebook account.

Comments on waterfordwhispersnews.com are moderated through the Facebook Comments Moderation tool.

You may delete this data from [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php) at any time.

### Email Contact by You

If you email waterfordwhispersnews.com with feedback or questions, we will respond to you as quickly as possible. Any details you send to us, including email and name, are stored for as long as is necessary to deal with your query. All contacts are deleted once we have satisfactorily answered your question or comment.

### Competition Winners List

We like to provide all readers with the names of winners of competitions. We will always request permission from the winner to display their name on the list and only display this for 3 months. Any winner has the right not to have their name published. There may be some instances of us not being able to display full names on our winners list for security or operational reasons.

## Services We Use

We use some third party services on our website. We only use GDPR compliant services and partners.

### Analytics Services

These services help us build a better website experience. We use Google Analytics. All of these services anonymise your IP and do not contain any personally identifiable information. Read their Privacy Policies by clicking on the links above. These companies do not share your data with any other companies. This information will never be disclosed to a third party, unless obliged to do so by a rule of law.

### Advertising

We schedule our advertising on site and in app with Google’s DoubleClick for Publishers. Any information collected and stored is non-personalised. Some cookies are used for non personalised ads. Read our [Cookies Policy](https://waterfordwhispersnews.com/your-privacy-settings/).

### Social Media & Website Players

waterfordwhispersnews.com offers readers the opportunity to share and view our content on various social media platforms, including Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, Google+, Instagram & Flickr.  
waterfordwhispersnews.com also uses GDPR compliant third party audio and video players as well as quiz generating tools. These include Youtube, Soundcloud and Playbuzz.

You can read each of their Privacy Policies by visiting:

## External Links

waterfordwhispersnews.com does provide links to other websites. Whilst we do check the validity of other websites and never link to any bogus websites, you should always check other website’s own Privacy Policies and Terms of Use.

We update our Privacy Policy from time to time as legislation and internal operating procedures change. Please keep an eye on this page for any updates or changes.

Contact our Data Protection Officer at info@waterfordwhispersnews.com for any further clarifications or personal data requests. Whilst we aim to address any questions or queries as soon as possible, please allow up to 30 working days for a response.

For more information on data protection, please visit [www.dataprotection.ie](https://www.dataprotection.ie/) & <https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection_en>
